<article>
	<preamble>ACL2004-HEADLINE.pdf</preamble>
	<title>Hybrid Headlines: Combining Topics and Sentence Compression David Zajic, Bonnie Dorr, Stacy President</title>
	<authors>Department of Computer ScienceUniversity of MarylandCollege Park, MD 20742dmzajic,bonnie @umiacs.umd.edustacypre@cs.umd.eduRichard SchwartzBBN Technologies9861 Broken Land Parkway, Suite 156Columbia, MD 21046schwartz@bbn.com</authors>
	<abstract>Abstract This paper presents Topiary, a headline- generation system that creates very short, informative summaries for news stories by combining sentence compres- sion and unsupervised topic discovery. We will show that the combination of linguistically motivated sentence com- pression with statistically selected topic terms performs better than either alone, according to some automatic summary evaluation measures. In addition we de- scribe experimental results establishing an appropriate extrinsic task on which to measure the effect of summarization on human performance. We demonstrate the usefulness of headlines in compar- ison to full texts in the context of this extrinsic task. </abstract>
	<biblio>ReferencesZhuoyan Li, and Frank Rudzicz. 2003. Usingmarization. In Proceedings of the 2003 Document92, Edmonton, Candada.2003a. Cross-language headline generation formation Processing (TALIP), 2:2.2003b. Hedge trimmer: A parse-and-trim approachNAACL 2003 Text Summarization Workshop, Ed-T. Euler. 2002. Tailoring text using topic words: Se-International Workshop on Database and Expertber 2002, Aix-en-Provence, France, pages 215–222.Kevin Knight and Daniel Marcu. 2000. Statistics-pression. In The 17th National Conference ofAAAI2000, Austin, Texas.tered representations on a text categorization task.ACM SIGIR conference on Research and develop-hagen, Denmark.matic Evaluation of Summaries Using N-gram Co-ference of the North American Chapter of the As-Alberta.English Front Page Headlines. Malmo.R. Schwartz, R. Stone, and R. Weischedel. 1998.Description of the SIFT System as Used for MUC-7.K. Papineni, S. Roukos, T. Ward, and W. Zhu. 2002.chine Translation. In Proceedings of Association ofR. Schwartz, T. Imai, F. Jubala, L. Nguyen, andfor topic classification of broadcast news. InDavid Zajic, Bonnie Dorr, Richard Schwartz, and Stacyresults, umiacs-tr-2004-18. Technical report, Uni-ing Studies, College Park, Maryland.marization at isi. In Proceedings of the 2003 Doc-pages 174–178, Edmonton, Candada.</biblio>
</article>
