<article>
	<preamble>compression_phrases_Prog-Linear-jair.pdf</preamble>
	<title>Global Inference for Sentence Compression An Integer Linear Programming Approach</title>
	<authors>James Clarke jclarke@ed.ac.ukMirella Lapata mlap@inf.ed.ac.ukSchool of InformaticsUniversity of Edinburgh2 Buccleuch PlaceEdinburgh EH8 9LW, UK</authors>
	<abstract>Abstract Sentence compression holds promise for many applications ranging from summarization to subtitle generation. Our work views sentence compression as an optimization problem and uses integer linear programming (ILP) to infer globally optimal compressions in the presence of linguistically motivated constraints. We show how previous formulations of sentence compression can be recast as ILPs and extend these models with novel global constraints. Experimental results on written and spoken texts demonstrate improvements over state-of-the-art models. </abstract>
	<biblio>Referencesbler. Journal of Computer and System Sciences, 3, 37–56.In Proceedings of the first International Conference on Natural Language Generation,Barzilay, R., & Lapata, M. (2006). Aggregation via set partitioning for natural languageNorth American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics, pp. 359–Bramsen, P., Deshpande, P., Lee, Y. K., & Barzilay, R. (2006). Inducing temporal graphs.Processing, pp. 189–198, Sydney, Australia.Proceedings of the Third International Conference on Language Resources and Eval-Charniak, E. (2000). A maximum-entropy-inspired parser. In Proceedings of the 1st North139, Seattle, WA, USA.domains, training requirements and evaluation measures. In Proceedings of the 21stthe Association for Computational Linguistics, pp. 377–384, Sydney, Australia.Cambridge toolkit. In Proceedings of Eurospeech’97, pp. 2707–2710, Rhodes, Greece.Cormen, T. H., Leiserson, C. E., & Rivest, R. L. (1992). Intoduction to Algorithms. TheCorston-Oliver, S. (2001). Text Compaction for Display on Very Small Screens. In Proceed-American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics, pp. 89–98, Pitts-Crammer, K., & Singer, Y. (2003). Ultraconservative online algorithms for multiclass prob-Dantzig, G. B. (1963). Linear Programming and Extensions. Princeton University Press,Denis, P., & Baldridge, J. (2007). Joint determination of anaphoricity and coreferenceConference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Lin-Dras, M. (1999). Tree Adjoining Grammar and the Reluctant Paraphrasing of Text. Ph.D.Galley, M., & McKeown, K. (2007). Lexicalized markov grammars for sentence compression.Linguistics, pp. 180–187, Rochester, NY, USA.R., & Hall, M. (Eds.), Combinatorial analysis, Proceedings of Symposia in AppliedGrefenstette, G. (1998). Producing Intelligent Telegraphic Text Reduction to Provide anof the AAAI Symposium on Intelligent Text Summarization, pp. 111–117, Stanford,Hori, C., & Furui, S. (2004). Speech summarization: an approach through word extractionD(1), 15–25.the 6th Applied Natural Language Processing Conference, pp. 310–315, Seattle,WA,Knight, K., & Marcu, D. (2002). Summarization beyond sentence extraction: a probabilisticLand, A. H., & Doig, A. G. (1960). An automatic method for solving discrete programmingLin, C.-Y. (2003). Improving summarization performance by sentence compression — a pilotAsian Languages, pp. 1–8, Sapporo, Japan.Language Technology Conference, pp. 222–227, San Francisco, CA, USA.Marciniak, T., & Strube, M. (2005). Beyond the pipeline: Discrete optimization in NLP. Inpp. 136–143, Ann Arbor, MI, USA.In Proceedings of the 11th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association forMcDonald, R., Crammer, K., & Pereira, F. (2005a). Flexible text segmentation with struc-ference and Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing, pp.McDonald, R., Crammer, K., & Pereira, F. (2005b). Online large-margin training of de-Linguistics, pp. 91–98, Ann Arbor, MI, USA.Interscience series in discrete mathematicals and opitmization. Wiley, New York, NY,Nguyen, M. L., Shimazu, A., Horiguchi, S., Ho, T. B., & Fukushi, M. (2004). Probabilisticnational conference on Computational Linguistics, pp. 743–749, Geneva, Switzerland.Recipes in C: The Art of Scientific Computing. Cambridge University Press, NewPunyakanok, V., Roth, D., Yih, W., & Zimak, D. (2004). Semantic role labeling via inte-Computational Linguistics, pp. 1346–1352, Geneva, Switzerland.dependency parsing. In Proceedings of the 2006 Conference on Empirical Methods inRiezler, S., King, T. H., Crouch, R., & Zaenen, A. (2003). Statistical sentence condensationgrammar. In Human Language Technology Conference and the 3rd Meeting of the125, Edmonton, Canada.Linguistics, 27(2), 249–276.In Proceedings of the 15th of the American Association for Artificial Intelligence, pp.Roth, D., & Yih, W. (2004). A linear programming formulation for global inference inNatural Language Learning, pp. 1–8, Boston, MA, USA.Roth, D., & Yih, W. (2005). Integer linear programming inference for conditional random744, Bonn.tion extraction. In Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems, Vancouver,Shieber, S., & Schabes, Y. (1990). Synchronous tree-adjoining grammars. In Proceed-Helsinki, Finland.compression. In Proceedings of the 43rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Com-Vandeghinste, V., & Pan, Y. (2004). Sentence compression for automated subtitling: AOut: Proceedings of the ACL-04 Workshop, pp. 89–95, Barcelona, Spain.Winston, W. L., & Venkataramanan, M. (2003). Introduction to Mathematical Program-Zajic, D., Door, B. J., Lin, J., & Schwartz, R. (2007). Multi-candidate reduction: SentenceManagement Special Issue on Summarization, 43(6), 1549–1570.</biblio>
</article>
