<article>
	<preamble>mikheev.pdf</preamble>
	<title>Periods, Capitalized Words, etc. Andrei Mikheev∗</title>
	<authors></authors>
	<abstract>University of Edinburgh In this article we present an approach for tackling three important aspects of text normaliza- tion: sentence boundary disambiguation, disambiguation of capitalized words in positions where capitalization is expected, and identification of abbreviations. As opposed to the two dominant techniques of computing statistics or writing specialized grammars, our document-centered ap- proach works by considering suggestive local contexts and repetitions of individual words within a document. This approach proved to be robust to domain shifts and new lexica and produced per- formance on the level with the highest reported results. When incorporated into a part-of-speech tagger, it helped reduce the error rate significantly on capitalized words and sentence boundaries. We also investigated the portability to other languages and obtained encouraging results. </abstract>
	<biblio>ReferencesDay, Lynette Hirschman, PatriciaDescription of the alembic system usedMessage Understanding Conference (MUC-6),Kaufmann.Reynar, Michael Niv, Bangalore Srinivas,extensible architecture for generalComputer-Assisted Information Searching onBaum, Leonard E. and Ted Petrie. 1966.functions of finite Markov chains. AnnalsBikel, Daniel, Scott Miller, Richard“Nymble: A high performance learningConference on Applied Natural LanguageWashington, D.C., Morgan Kaufmann.error-driven learning and naturalpart-of-speech tagging. ComputationalBrill, Eric. 1995b. “Unsupervised learning oftagging.” In David Yarovsky and KennethWorkshop on Very Large Corpora, pagesfor Computational Linguistics.Users. Centre for Lexical Information,Mikheev Periods, Capitalized Words, etc.MUC-7.” In Seventh Message UnderstandingConference Held in Fairfax, April. MorganChurch, Kenneth. 1988. “A stochastic partsunrestricted text.” In Proceedings of theLanguage Processing (ANLP’88), pagesChurch, Kenneth. 1995. “One term or two?”International ACM SIGIR Conference onRetrieval, pages 310–318, Seattle,Clarkson, Philip and Anthony J. Robinson.mixtures and an exponentially decayingConference on Speech and Signal Processing,Cucerzan, Silviu and David Yarowsky. 1999.recognition combining morphological andJoint SIGDAT Conference on EMNLP andFrancis, W. Nelson and Henry Kucera. 1982.and Grammar. Houghton Mifflin, NewGale, William, Kenneth Church, and Daviddiscourse.” In Proceedings of the FourthWorkshop, pages 233–237.1994. “What is a word, what is aThe Proceedings of Third Conference onResearch (COMPLEX’94), Budapest,Krupka, George R. and Kevin Hausman.netowl extractor system as used forMessage Understanding Conference (MUC-7),Kuhn, Roland and Renato de Mori. 1998. Aspeech recognition. IEEE Transactions on12:570–583.tagging using a hidden Markov model.Mani, Inderjeet and T. Richard MacMillan.names in newswire text.” In B. BoguraevProcessing for Lexical Acquisition. MIT Press,Marcus, Mitchell, Mary Ann Marcinkiewicz,large annotated corpus of English: The19(2):313–329.induction for unknown word guessing.Mikheev, Andrei. 1999. A knowledge-freedisambiguation. In Proceedings of the 37thComputational Linguistics (ACL’99), pagesPark.boundaries.” In Proceedings of the FirstComputational Linguistics (NAACL’2000),Morgan Kaufmann.Matheson. 1998. TTT: Text Tokenisation Tool.of Edinburgh. Available atindex.html.Moens. 1998. Description of the ltgMessage Understanding ConferenceFairfax, Virginia. Morgan Kaufmann.1995. Russian morphology: AnEngineering 1(3):235–260.“Adaptive sentence boundaryFourth ACL Conference on Applied Natural78–83, Stuttgart, Germany, October.Palmer, David D. and Marti A. Hearst. 1997.disambiguation. Computational LinguisticsPark, Youngja and Roy J. Byrd. 2001.abbreviations and their definitions.” InMethods in Natural Language ProcessingD.C. Morgan Kaufmann.entropy model for part-of-speech318tagging.” In Proceedings of Conference onProcessing, pages 133–142, University ofReynar, Jeffrey C. and Adwait Ratnaparkhi.identifying sentence boundaries.” InApplied Natural Language ProcessingKaufmann.of tree-based modeling to speech andDARPA Speech and Natural LanguageKaufmann.collocation.” In Proceedings of ARPApages 266–271, Princeton, New Jersey.word sense disambiguation rivalingAssociation for Computational Linguistics</biblio>
</article>
